all right good afternoon everybody
没事，大家下午好
welcome good to see you all welcome also
欢迎很高兴见到你所有也欢迎
to our viewers on video so last week we
我们对视频所以上周我们的观众
looked at this this virtual memory
看着这本虚拟内存
mechanism and how it provides so many
机制以及它如何提供这么 多
different useful functionalities to the
不同有用的功能的
system along with this sort of
有了这样 的系统一起
abstraction of having this large
具有这种大型的抽象
contiguous array of bytes now once we're
字节的连续数组现在一旦我们
given that that large array of bytes now
鉴于该大阵列的 字节 现在
we have to manage it and we have to we
我们必须要管理它，我们有我们
have to have some mechanism to to manage
必须有某种 机制来管理
and use that that resource okay so
并使用该资源好了，
that's the topic of our our lectures
这是我们对我们的讲座 话题
this week is storage allocation and how
本周是存储分配 和如何
storage allocators work and how you use
存储分配器的工作以及您如何使用
them to manage them there the virtual
他们来管理 他们那里的虚拟
memory in your system so the basic idea
您的系统内存，因此基本思路
of a dynamic memory allocator is that
动态存储器的分配器 是
applications use it to to manipulate
应用程序使用它来操纵
virtual memory to create to to allocate
虚拟存储器来创建到分配
and free chunks of virtual memory that
内存 和 虚拟内存的 空闲 块是
you need in your program and it's this
你在你的程序需要和它的这个
memory is maintained in it in an area of
存储器被保持在它在的区域
virtual memory called the heap ok and
虚拟存储器称为堆 确定和
almost all languages have some ask some
几乎所有的语言有一定的问 一些
mechanism for for acquiring and
机构，用于获取和
manipulating this this this dynamic
操纵这个这个这个动态
memory so in NC it's a phone it's the
内存所以在NC它是一个手机它的
malloc package languages like Java have
像Java的malloc包的语言 有
the new you know the new method
新的你知道新方法
now the allocator the allocator
现在分配器分配器
maintains the heap as a contiguous
保持堆作为连续
collection of blocks where it blocks can
块的集合，其中它块 可以
be allocated or free
被分配或免费
okay allocated meaning that they're
好分配这意味着 他们
they're being used by some program
他们正在使用的一些程序
application free meaning that they're
申请免费的含义，他们是
available to be for use by an
可以是使用由
application and there's there's two
应用和有有两家
types of allocators the kind of
类型的分配器有种
allocator that you find in c such as the
你在C发现，如分配器
malloc package it's up to the
malloc的包装是达
application to both explicitly allocate
应用程序 都明确地分配
the the memory and explicitly free it
在内存和明确地释放它
when when the when the application is
当，当， 当应用程序是
finished with it okay so the system
完成了它好了，所以系统
won't won't free up any memory that you
不会不会释放任何内存，你
allocate unless you do it explicitly by
分配除非你做它明确
calling the by calling the free function
通过调用free函数调用
but there's other languages that that
但有其他语言说
support implicit allocators and in these
支持这些隐式分配器和
and these implicit allocators the
这些隐含的分配器
programmer explicitly allocates memory
程序员明确地分配内存
but then the system takes care of
但随后该系统需要照顾
freeing the memory okay so it's that the
释放内存 好了，那就是在
burden of freeing the memory is shifted
释放内存的负担转移
from the application program to the to
从应用程序到到
the system and it it frees this memory
该系统和它它释放该内存
implicitly sort of behind the scenes
隐式类型的幕后
using a process called garbage
使用这个过程 被称为 垃圾
collection okay so languages like Java
收集好了，所以像Java语言
ml Lisp they all they all do implicit
毫升的Lisp他们都他们都做隐
implicit they all support and close at
隐性他们都支持，密切在
allocators now today we're going to just
分配器现在今天我们要公正
we're going to discuss explicit memory
我们要讨论外显记忆
alligators on Thursday we'll get into
周四 鳄鱼 ，我们将进入
implicit alligators and how they work
隐含的鳄鱼和它们如何工作
now the allocator and see is provided it
现在分配器和看到的是它提供
by the standard c library in a set of
通过在一组 标准C库
function called malloc package the the
函数调用malloc的包中
malloc function is used to to allocate
malloc函数是用来分配
memory and it takes as input a size
存储器，并将其作为输入的尺寸
argument which is in bytes okay and then
参数，它是在字节好，然后
it returns a pointer to a to a memory
它返回一个指向到存储器
block that contains at least size bytes
块包含至少size个字节
and that block is aligned T on x86
并且该块被对准 T于86
systems to 8 bytes on x86 64 systems to
系统，以8个字节在 x86 64个系统
16 bytes if size is zero it return to no
16个字节，如果大小为零它 回归 到 无
and then it returns -1 like like most
然后返回-1喜欢最喜欢的
typical system calls the programmer
典型的系统调用程序员
frees memory by calling the free
通过调用自由释放内存
function it takes as an argument a
功能需要作为自变量的
pointer that was returned from some
这 是从一些返回的指针
prior indication of malloc and it
malloc和它的先前指示
returns nothing and it frees that I've
没有返回值，也能够让我已经
given this pointer that was returned by
鉴于此指针被退回
the prior indication of malloc it frees
的malloc的先前指示它释放
the block at that address and then
块在该地址，然后
returns that block to the pool of
该块返回到 池
available memory now there's some
可用内存现在有一些
there's some other functions sialic is a
还有一些其他的功能唾液酸是
version of malloc that gives you an
malloc的版本，给你一个
initialized block of memory that's
内存初始化块是
initialized to 0 and realloc you can you
初始化为0和realloc您可以在
can malloc a block and then call realloc
可以MALLOC一个块，然后调用的realloc
to change the size of that previously
以前改变了大小
allocated block and then there's a
分配的块，然后有一个
function called S break which is used
其中使用函数称为S破
internally by allocators to to grow and
内部由分配器来成长，
shrink the heap so when an allocator
缩小堆，因此，在分配器
needs more memory it calls S break 2 to
需要更多的内存调用 分手吧2〜
get that additional virtual memory and
获得额外的虚拟 内存和
then that that's added to the heat that
那么了加 的热量
proportion that grows the heap and then
比例，生长堆，然后
it adds it to the memory that the the
它其添加到内存 中的
allocators is manipulating
分配器被操纵
so here's an example of how we would use
所以这里我们将如何 用一个例子
malloc and it's in a simple program we
malloc 和它在一个简单的程序 ，我们
have a pointer to an int P and we call
有一个指针为int P和我们所说的
malloc and we we want to allocate an
malloc 和我们 ， 我们要 分配一个
array of n imps so this is that this is
的n个阵列IMPS 所以这是这是
sort of the standard way you call it we
排序的标准方式调用它，我们
want an int and so we call it with n
想要一个int，所以我们有n叫它
times the size event it because remember
倍大事件，因为记得
the argument is in bytes malloc returns
参数为以字节为单位的malloc返回
a pointer it returns a generic pointer
一个指针，它返回一个通用指针
void star pointer so we cast it to a
空星指针，所以我们将其转换为一个
pointer to an int to keep the compiler
指向int 使 编译器
happy and then assign it to 2p we check
快乐，然后将其分配给2P我们检查
for a we check for a null return value
对于 空返回值 的我们检查
so I should I should point out the it
所以我应该我应该指出的是
returns zero on air so we check we
返回空气为零，以便我们 检查
recheck recheck for this know the smell
复检复查该知道的气味
pointer which is 0 and print an error if
指针是0，并且 如果 打印错误
it's no now once we've got that pointer
它没有现在一旦我们得到了指针的
now P we can treat it just like an array
现在我们P可以把它就像一个数组
so we can so inside the loop if we want
所以我们可以这样循环中，如果我们想
to initialize it we loop across the
初始化它，我们在整个环
elements of the array
该阵列的元件
initializing each one to some value now
现在初始化每一个到某一值
when we're finished when we're finished
当我们的时候，我们就完蛋就完蛋了
with this chunk of memory that we've
与此块的内存 ， 我们已经
allocated then we free it by calling
分配后，我们通过调用释放它
free with the pointer P
自由与指针P
okay now the so we're going to look
现在没事了，所以我们要看看
today at how functions like malloc and
今天怎么样的malloc函数和
free are implemented so we're going to
免费实现，所以我们打算
make a few simplifying assumptions so
做一些简单的假设，从而
I'm going to memory is byte address we
我要去内存字节地址我们
know that but for the purposes of this
知道，但本作的目的
lecture we're going to assume that it's
讲座我们将 假定它是
it's word address okay so we're just
它的字 地址好了，所以我们只是
going to look at word size units and I'm
去看看字大小的单位和我
going to assume that words are 4 bytes
将假设词语是4个字节
so basically the size of an int so this
一个int所以基本上大小，使这
isn't actually this this isn't true I
实际上不是这样，这是不是真正的我
need to fix that so basically we're
要解决 这个 问题 所以基本上我们
going to we're going to think of words
要我们要思考的话
that's for byte quantity sort of integer
这 对字节 数量排序整数
sized quantities and then our blocks or
大小的数量，然后我们的块或
contiguous chunks of those words that
这些词语连续块那
can be either allocated or free so here
既可以分配或免费的，所以在这里
we have a portion of the heap which
我们有堆的一部分，其
consists of a forward allocated block
由 前分配块 的
followed by a two-word free block
后跟一个 双字的空闲块
followed by another forward allocated
紧接着又向前分配
block followed by a three word free
块， 然后免费三个词
blocking and we'll indicate these free
阻挡， 我们将指出这些免费
blocks by by white and will indicate
块由白色和将指示
allocated blocks with some some shade of
与一些树荫一些分配的块
color so let's look now how a sequence
颜色，所以现在让我们看看如何序列
of allocations and freeze would work and
分配和冻结将工作和
now notice I'm calling malloc with the
现在请注意，我调用malloc与
size of in words not bytes just to keep
在话不是字节只是为了保持规模
just to keep things keep these pictures
只是为了让事情保持这些图片
simpler
简单
so in this first we call malloc and
所以在此我们首先调用 malloc 和
allocate of a forward block then we
正向块的分配，然后我们
canet and that gives us a pointer P 1
卡内特这给了我们一个指针P1
then we call malloc again to get a
然后我们再次调用malloc获得
five-word block so it just takes it one
五字块，它只是需要 它一个
of the free words and allocates it we
自由的话，并分配它，我们
call malloc again to get a six word
再次调用malloc 获得 六个字
block and then we free the block that's
块，然后我们释放这就是块
pointed at by P to this purple block
在用P 指向此紫块
okay so now we that frees up that block
好了，所以现在我们是释放了 块
and then we do another allocation for a
然后我们做了另一种分配
two word block and so the the allocator
两条字块等的分配器
looks to see if it can find a free block
看起来，看它是否能找到一个空闲块
that has enough enough room and it finds
具有足够足够的空间，它会找出
that it finds this free block here that
它在这里 ， 认为这空闲块
has five free words and then it
有5分免费的话，然后将其
allocates the requested block inside of
分配的内部所请求的块
that that free block now allocators work
这是免费的块现在分配器工作
under a lot of a lot of different
下了很多很多不同的
constraints so it's hard to write an
约束，所以很难写一个
allocator because of all these
因为所有这些分配器
constraints applications can choose any
限制的应用可以选择任何
combination of allocated and free blocks
分配和空闲块的组合
so you can't predict what what an
所以你不能预测什么什么的
application is going to request and and
应用程序将请求与和
the application is required to free a
应用程序释放所需
block by when it frees a block to pass a
通过时它释放 块的块传递一个
pointer that was returned from a
这是从返回的指针
previous invocation of malloc okay so
的malloc调用以前好了，
the the application has a few
该应用程序有几个
constraints but but really the only one
约束，但是但实际上 只有一个
that it has is that the fact that the
它具有 的是事实，
when it frees something it has to be a
当它释放的东西它是 一个
pointer from previous invocation of
从以前调用指针
malloc now the malloc operates or
现在的malloc malloc的操作或
allocators like malloc operate under a
喜欢的malloc分配器下运行
lot of different constraints they can't
很多不同的 限制，他们不能
control the size or the number of the
控制大小或数
allocated blocks because they have no
分配的块，因为他们没有
control over the what the application is
在该应用程序是什么 控制
doing if an application calls Malik
做的，如果应用程序调用马利克
Malik has to respond right away it might
马利克必须马上它可能响应
you might be able to do a better more
你也许可以做一个更好的更
efficient version by batching up
有效的版本， 按配料了
requests and then responding to all
请求 ，然后响应所有
those requests at once
同时这些请求
but the allocator can't do it when it
但分配器不能当它这样做
gets called it has to process the
被调用时 ， 必须 处理
request and then return right away it
请求， 然后立即返回 它
has to of course it has to allocate
有，当然有 分配
blocks from free memory so it can't
从空闲内存块，因此它不能
in general I can't touch any allocated
总的来说，我不能碰 任何分配
block right once it allocates a block
阻断右一旦它分配一个块
that block belongs to the application
该块所属的应用程序
and the malloc package can't touch it
和malloc的包 无法触摸它
now this has a number of implications so
现在这个有一些影响， 这样
this means that the allocator can't it
这意味着分配器不就可以了
can't move blocks around like it can't
不能走动块喜欢的话可以不
compress blocks like an alligator might
压缩块鳄鱼般的力量
want to take allocated blocks and smoosh
要采取分配的块和smoosh
them all together to create larger free
他们都共同创造 更大的自由
blocks okay but it can't do that okay so
块不错，但它不能这样做， 所以没关系
once you know in a language like C once
一旦你在 像C 语言知道 一旦
once an alligator gives a block to an
一旦鳄鱼给出了一个块到
application it can't touch it
应用程序不能触摸它
okay now blocks like blocks because
现在没事了块像块，因为
blocks are holding data structures like
块保持的数据结构如
structs or you know scalar scalar
结构或你认识的标标
objects it has to be aligned to the size
反对它必须对齐大小
of the largest object that that can
最大的对象 ， 它可以
occur okay so for 64-bit systems that's
所以对于64位系统这是发生没关系
16 byte alignment for 32-bit systems
用于32位系统16字节对齐
it's 8 byte alignment
这是 8字节对齐
now alligators are really interesting
现在短吻鳄是真的很有趣
objects because they they combine a
对象，因为他们他们结合了
trade-off of both sort of running times
这两个种类 的运行 时间 的权衡
sort of speed and space so it's kind of
那种速度和空间，因此它是一种
a space and performance trade-off you're
一个空间和性能的权衡你
trying to optimize both you want it to
试图以优化 你 想让它
run as quickly as possible but you want
运行尽可能 快的 ，但 你要
to use you want it to use the virtual
用你 想要使用虚拟
memory in the heap as efficiently as
存储器堆中 尽可能有效地
possible okay so let's now we define
可能还好所以现在我们定义让我们
these these sort of speed and and
这些这些排序的速度和和
efficiency memory efficiency metrics we
效率内存效率指标我们
have we have two metrics that we use one
有，我们有我们使用一个两个指标
is called throughput so given some
如此提供所谓的吞吐量一些
sequence of malloc and free requests are
（）和malloc的序列自由请求是
0 through R n minus 1 so just some where
0至 R n 减1，从而只是一些地方
R is either a malloc or free our goal is
R 是一个malloc或 免费的 我们的目标是
to maximize throughput and the peak
以最大化吞吐量和峰值
memory utilization and what makes malloc
内存利用率，是什么让的malloc
such a fascinating and interesting study
这样的迷人和有趣的研究
is that these often conflict like it's
是，这些 往往喜欢它的冲突
very easy to make a really fast malloc
很容易做出 一个非常快的malloc
that that has terrible memory
以使得具有可怕的记忆
utilization so throughput is just the
利用这样的吞吐量仅仅是
number of recomputed requests per unit
每单位重新计算请求的数目
time so we have 5,000 malloc calls and
时间，让我们有 5000 malloc的调用和
5,000 free calls in 10 seconds then our
在10秒内5000个免费电话，然后我们
throughput is a thousand operations per
吞吐量是每一千操作
second so it's just measuring sort of
第二所以它只是衡量排序
how efficiently are our malloc can can
如何有效是我们的malloc可以可以
process these requests from an
处理来自这些请求
application
应用
now peak memory utilization is a measure
现在高峰内存利用率是衡量
sort of how how much useful space sort
如何排序多少有用的空间排序
of how much it measures how efficiently
多少它的措施如何有效
the allocator uses the heat sort of how
分配器可使用热之类的怎么样
much is wasted on sort of overhead in
多浪费在这类开销在
the data structures that the allocator
数据结构，所述分配器
has to use us to in its implementation
在其方案中使用我们
so we'll define a payload when when
因此，我们将定义一个有效载荷时，当
malloc returns a block what when it I'm
的malloc返回一个块时，我什么
sorry when an application makes a call
抱歉，当应用程序进行调用
to malloc it's a questing a certain size
对malloc这是一个 探路 一定规模
block and that that block is called the
块 与 该块被称为
payload so if we call malloc with an
有效载荷，所以如果我们调用malloc与
argument of 10 bytes we're requesting a
10个字节 我们请求一个 说法
block that has a payload of it that's at
块有它的有效载荷是在
least size 10 ok and the 10 bytes that
至少10大小确定和 10个字节，其
we request that are called the payload
我们要求 被称为有效载荷
everything else in that block is is
一切都在那个块是其他
overhead ok
开销确定
so after after we've run a sequence of
打完之后，我们已经运行的序列
requests the aggregate payload is the
要求总有效载荷是
sum of all the payloads in the currently
在目前所有的有效载荷的总和
allocated block okay so in a perfect
分配块好了，所以在一个完美的
allocator the the aggregate payload
分配器的总有效载荷
would would would equal the amount of
将将将等于的量
memory the total size of all the
内存的所有总规模
allocated blocks or because there'd be
分配的块或因为有会是
no overhead would just be would just be
没有开销也只是 也只是
pure every block would be pure payload
纯的每个块将是纯的有效载荷
now we're going to assume that the heap
现在我们要假定堆
is is monotonically non-decreasing so it
是单调非递减，因此
always gets bigger okay so our this is a
总是得到更大的好了 ，所以 我们这是一个
simplifying assumption it's not it's not
简化假设它 没有它不是
true in a real malloc package but we'll
在一个真正的malloc包真实的，但我们会
just assume that the allocator never
只是假设，分配器从来没有
decreases the size of the heap it only
减小堆的 大小 ，只
increases the size of the heap okay so
增加堆的大小好了，
the peek given those given those notions
鉴于偷看那些给出这些概念
of aggregate payload and heap size the
骨料有效载荷和堆大小的
peak memory utilization after k plus 1
k加1后的峰值存储器利用率
requests is the sum of all the is the
要求是所有的总和是
sum of all the payloads divided by the
由分割的所有有效载荷的总和
total size of the heap so the in the
堆的总大小，因此在
best case each each block in the heap
最好的情况下的每个中的每个堆块
consists of pure payload so the
由纯有效载荷因此的
utilization would be 1 that's the best
利用将1 这是最好的
we can do but in in in practice each
我们可以做的，但 在每次练习
block the allocator is going to place
块分配器是要去的地方
have data structures and padding inside
具有内部数据结构和填充
of each block that that that keep it
每个阻止这是保持它
from getting a perfect utilization now
从现在得到一个完美的利用
one one obvious thing is that since
一个一个明显的一点是，由于
blocks have to be aligned to some you
块必须对齐到一些你
know if there's sixteen by two lines
知道是否有十六岁 的 两条 线
then blocks have to start on 16 by
然后块都由开始于16
boundaries and they have to be at least
边界， 他们必须至少
16 bytes so if you were to request a
16个字节，因此如果你要申请
payload of 2 bytes you'd have a lot of
2个字节的有效载荷你有很多的
wasted bytes right that would sort of
浪费字节正确的，会有点
decrease the utilization so this is some
降低利用率，所以这是一些
some of this some of this overhead is
一些这方面的一些这种开销是
unavoidable but your job as a
不可避免的，但作为你的工作
someone who writes a implements Malik is
有人谁写的 一个工具 是马利克
to try to keep that as small as possible
要尽量保留尽可能小
so poor memory utilization it's this
所以内存利用率较低正是这种
example that we just talked about is an
例如，我们刚才讲 的是一个
example of what we call fragmentation
例如我们所说的碎片
and there's there's two types of
而且也有两种类型的
fragmentation internal fragmentation
碎片内部碎片
occurs if the payload is smaller than
发生如果有效载荷 小于
the block size those just what we're
块大小 的 正是我们
we're talking about and this can be
我们谈论这样就可以
caused by either padding in the block or
在块而导致的任何 填充或
some kind of data structure in the block
某种数据结构的块中的
that the allocator needs sometimes to
该分配器有时需要
you might make a policy decision that if
你可能会做出政策决定 ，如果
it if application requests a small block
它如果应用程序请求一小块
you might return a larger block just to
你可能会返回一个更大的块刚
keep so the blocks don't get sort of
保持这样的块没有得到几分
splintered up into little chunk you
分裂成小块，你
might want to keep blocks at some
可能想保留块在一些
minimum size
最小尺寸
now internal fragmentation you know
现在内部碎片 ，你知道
given a series of requests we can we can
给出了一系列的要求，我们可以，我们可以
just stop and freeze the heat and it's
只是停止和 冻结的热量和它的
very easy to so it computes the amount
很容易，因此计算量
of internal fragmentation we can at any
内部碎片，我们可以在任何
point in time we can just look at all
在时间点上，我们可以只看 所有
the previous requests that we we've made
我们我们所做的以前的请求
and and look at the size of the payload
和并期待在有效载荷的大小
for each one of those requests and so we
这些请求中的每一个，因此我们
can so we can determine the level you
可以这样我们就可以判断你的水平
know get at a point in time we can
及时了解情况获得在一个点上，我们可以
determine the level of internal
确定的内部水平
fragmentation just by looking at the
碎片 只是通过看
previous requests so there's another
以前的请求 ，因此有另
form of fragmentation called external
碎片的形式称为外部
fragmentation which is a little more
碎片是多一点
difficult to to deal with so external
很难对付这样的外部
fragmentation occurs when there's enough
当有足够的发生碎裂
memory in the heap but there's there's
内存堆中，但有有
no single free block that can satisfy a
没有单一的自由块可满足
particular request ok so external
特定请求 确定，所以外部
fragmentation occurs when the
碎片时发生
application makes a request for a block
应用使一个块的请求
but nowhere in the heap is there a free
但无处在堆中有一个免费的
block that's large enough to to satisfy
块的大到足以满足
that request
该请求
so an example of this like suppose
所以这样的一个例子 假设
here's the previous example we looked at
这里是我们看着前面的例子
now where we have after a series of
现在，我们有经过一系列的
malloc and free calls we have two free
malloc和免费电话，我们有两个免费
blocks in the heap one containing five
在含有5堆一个块
words and the other containing two words
单词和另 一种含有两个词
so the total the total number of free
所以总的自由总数
words in our heap is seven seven words
在我们堆的话是七七话
and now we get a request for six words
现在我们得到 六个字 的 要求
okay we have enough free blocks we have
还好我们有我们有足够的空闲块
enough free words in the heap but we
在人堆里， 但是 我们足够的话
can't satisfy that request and it's
不能满足这一要求，它的
because of it's because of this
因为 它是因为 这个
phenomenon called external fragmentation
现象称为外部碎片
for example if we'd have if we'd have
例如，如果我们不得不如果我们不得不
somehow allocated
不知何故分配
yeah I don't know in this case I don't
是啊，我不知道在这种情况下， 我不
think we could have avoided the external
我想 我们本来 可以避免外部
fragmentation but nonetheless there's
碎片，但仍然有
enough memory here we just it's the way
足够的内存在这里我们只是它的方式
that our blocks are configured in the
我们的模块 在配置
heap we can't satisfy the request so in
堆，我们不能满足该 请求，以便在
this in this in this case that the
这本在这种情况下，该
allocator has to go and get more more
分配器具有去获得更多的更
virtual memory would have to go and it
虚拟内存会去 和 它
would have to get more virtual memory
必须获得更多的虚拟内存
and extend the heap out this way and to
和扩展堆了这种方式，并
get a large enough free block so you
得到一个 足够 大 的空闲块，所以你
know assessing and sort of understanding
知道评估和体悟
external fragmentation is difficult
外部碎片很难
because unlike internal fragmentation
因为不像内部碎片
which depended on the previous request
其依赖于先前的请求
external fragmentation depends on future
外部碎片取决于未来
requests so if we look back at this
请求因此，如果我们在 此 回顾
point we say is our is our heap
一点上，我们说的 是 我们的就是我们的堆
externally fragmented well we it depends
外部碎片以及我们这取决于
right we can't say it turns out it is
正确的，我们不能说原来它是
because the next request is is for a
因为下一个请求是为
block of size six but if all of the
大小的6块，但如果所有的
future blocks are future requests were
未来块 是未来的要求是
four below we're four blocks of you know
四个 ，你 下面我们 四个街区知道
say small blocks then we be able to
说小块，然后 我们才能
satisfy those and we wouldn't we
满足这些，我们不会，我们
wouldn't suffer from external
不会从 外部 遭受
fragmentation
碎片
okay now when we build an alligator all
现在没事了，当我们建立一个 所有 鳄鱼
kinds of issues come up and said I've
各种各样的问题来 了， 说我有
glossed over with my simple examples
轻轻带过我简单的例子
right you know how do we know if we call
正确的 你知道我们怎么 知道，如果我们所说的
free how does free know how much memory
免费如何免费知道多少内存
to free up right we don't call free with
腾出正确的，我们不叫自由搭配
the block size we call it with a pointer
块大小，我们用指针调用它
so how does three know how big that
所以如何做 三知道如何之大，
block is how do we keep track of all the
块是我们如何保持跟踪所有
free blocks when we have you know when
空闲块时，我们有你知道什么时候
we're satisfying an allocation request
我们要满足分配请求
we're going to fight we're going to look
我们要争取我们要去看看
for a free block that is larger than the
为空闲块比所述较大
requested size on that that case what do
对这种情况下做什么所需大小
we do with the extra space in the block
我们做与块的额外空间
we do we just keep it in the block you
我们做我们只是 把它放在你的块
know and and suffer some internal
了解和受苦一些内部
fragmentation do we split that block
碎片做我们拆分块
into a smaller block there's a lot of
成更小的块 有很多 的
free blocks in the in the heap how do we
在空闲块堆中我们怎么样
when we make an out when the allocator
当我们做一个出来的时候， 分配器
gets a allocation request how does it
获得一个分配请求是怎么做的
pick from all among all of those
从所有挑中所有的
different free blocks
不同的空闲块
there's many choices and then once when
有很多选择 ，然后一旦当
free tries to insert a free block we're
免费尝试插入空闲块我们
in the heap you know where does it
在人堆里你知道它在哪里
insert it okay when it's when it's free
插入它好时，它的时候 它是免费的
and how do we reinsert a free block what
以及我们如何重新插入空闲块什么
does that mean so today we're going to
这是否意味着今天， 所以 我们要去
look at all of these issues starting
看看所有这些问题 开始
with knowing how much to free so how big
有知道多少免费的，所以有多大
our block sizes so the typical the
我们的块大小，因此典型
standard method is to keep sort of a
标准方法是保持排序的
word sized quantity at the beginning of
在年初字大小的量
each block that gives the size of that
每个 给出的所述大小的 块
block in in some units I'm showing them
阻断在一些 单位，我向他们展示
here in word size units okay so that if
在这里字长单位好了，所以，如果
if the application Malick's a payload of
如果应用程序马利克是 一个有效载荷
size wants to want to now like a payload
大小要要 像现在的有效载荷
of size four then the allocator needs to
四个大小则分配器需要
find a block
找块
of size five so consisting of four
大小五个因此由四个
payload words at least four payload
有效载荷字至少四个有效载荷
words and then a header block had to be
字，然后报头块必须是
a header word at the beginning that that
一开始是一个字头
indicates the size the total size of
表示的尺寸的总尺寸
that block and then it returns a pointer
该块 ，然后将它返回一个指针
p0 in this case to the beginning of the
P0 在这种情况下的开始
payload okay
有效载荷好吗
okay so now we know how big each block
好了，现在我们知道 每块 有多大
is that's pretty simple and how we keep
是，是很简单的 ，以及我们如何保持
track of the free block and this is
跟踪空闲块的， 这是
where it gets interesting the simplest
它 有趣的 是最简单
method is to use that we call an
方法是使用我们称之为
implicit list an implicit list of free
隐列表免费的隐式列表
blocks and the idea here is to just put
块和这里的想法 是只放
a header in the front of every block in
在每一个块的 前部的头
the heap whether allocated or free and
无论是分配的还是免费的 ，堆
then we can use that starting at the
那么我们就可以使用 起始于
beginning of the heap we can use that
堆的开始，我们可以使用
size to walk the heap okay so here's a
大小走路堆好了，这里有一个
block of size five so we can we can jump
大小的 5块，所以我们可以，我们可以 跳
we know that the next block starts at an
我们知道下一块开始在
offset of five with the second block we
五与 第二块，我们偏移
know the then the next block starts at
知道再下一块开始于
an offset of four and so on
四个偏移等
okay so we call it an implicit free list
好了，所以我们把它称为一个隐含的空闲列表
because there's there's no real list of
因为有有没有真正的名单
free blocks but we can't we can't
免费块，但我们不能我们 不能
reverse that all of the free blocks in
反向所有的空闲块的
the heap by traversing all of the blocks
堆通过遍历所有的块
in the heat and then just ignoring the
在热，然后就忽略
the allocated blocks okay so
分配的块好了，
now another thing we could do is we
现在我们可以做的另一件事是 ，我们
could actually use some of the some of
实际上可以使用 一些些的
the words in the block to create a
在块中的字来创建
linked list of some kind either singly
某种 链表 单独
or doubly linked lists and in this case
或双向链表 ，在这种情况下，
we it's an explicit list of the free
我们是自由的显式列表
blocks and we can just walk that list so
块，我们就可以在 这个列表 里 如此
we here we visit the first free block
我们在这里，我们参观的第一个空闲块
and then there's a pointer to the next
然后有一个指向下一个
free block and so on so this you see
空闲块等等所以这个你看
this might be a little more efficient
这可能是一个小更高效
because if we want to traverse the free
因为如果我们想要自由穿越
list in this case if it's going to be
列出在这种情况下，如果它的 将是
ordered the number of blocks in the list
有序列表 中 的块数
okay it's going to be linear in the
还好它会 在被线性
total number of blocks in the heap which
在堆 块的总数 ，其
might be quite large there could be lots
可能是 相当大的 可能有很多
of allocated blocks in this case with an
的分配块在这种情况下用
explicit list any traversal just just be
显式列表中的任意穿越才刚刚是
linear in the size of the free list
在空闲列表的大小呈线性关系
question
题
yeah that's the question is don't we
是啊，这问题是 我们不
need a free bit and we do and I'll we
需要一个免费的一下，我们这样做， 我会我们
have that's the next question
有那下一个问题
now another method a more sophisticated
现在另一种方法更复杂
method instead of having one free list
方法，而不是具有一个自由列表
we can have multiple free lists where
我们可以有多个空闲列表哪里
each free list contains blocks of a
每个自由列表中包含的块
certain size or certain range of sizes
一定的大小或一定范围内的 尺寸 的
or we can get really fancy and use some
或者我们可以得到真正看中的 ，并使用一些
kind of some kind of a balance tree to
那种某种平衡树 来 的
sort the blocks to use the tree to sort
块排序使用树 排序
them by size order now today we're going
他们按大小顺序现在今天我们
to look at the implicit list the
看隐含名单
simplest kind of free list and this will
最简单的空闲列表，这将
identify a lot of basic concepts that
找出了很多基本概念
are used in the more sophisticated free
在更复杂的免费 使用
list questions okay the question is what
名单的问题 还好，问题是什么
do you what do we mean by different free
你什么意思，我们通过不同的自由
lists for different size classes so what
针对不同规模类列表等什么
I mean is that you identify a range of
我的意思 是，你确定 一系列的
sizes and you associate that range with
尺寸和您 范围内 关联
with each of these individual free lists
与这些个人自由列表
okay so one free list might hold blocks
好了，所以一个空闲列表可能会保留块
of size 0 to 8 and another free list
大小0-8和其他空闲列表
might hold blocks of size 9 to 16 and
可能拥有大小9块到16
the other another free list may be 17 to
其他另一个自由列表可能17
32 you know some and so you're
32 你知道一些，因此你
guaranteed you now know when you're
保证你现在知道，当你
traversing a certain list you know the
穿越你知道某个列表
range of sizes of the blocks in that
在于：所述块的大小的范围
list the reason you might want to do
列出你可能想要 做的原因
that by the way is that imagine you had
通过的方式是，想像 你有
an infinite number of of these lists one
这些列表一个无限 多
for each possible size then every time
对于每 一次 每一个可能的大小，然后
you allocated a block you'd get a block
您分配的块，你会得到一个块
of exactly the size you needed so
正是大小的你需要这样
there'd be a minimum amount of
有会是最小量
fragmentation if you had an infinite
碎片如果你有无限
number of these of these size classes
这些这些尺寸课程数量
now if we of course we can't have an
现在，如果我们当然我们不能 有
infinite number but the more of these
无限数量，但这些更
size classes we have the closer we get
大小班，我们越是接近
to that ideal
这个理想
all right so let's look at how we would
没事所以让我们看看 会怎样
build in implicit free list so as you
建立隐含免费 列表 ，从而你
correctly point it out for for each each
正确地指出来为每个每个
block we need we need both sides and the
块中，我们需要，我们需要双方 和
allocation status question why can't we
分配状态的问题，为什么 我们不能
map every size class
映射各种规模类
yeah that's so why can't we have an
是的，这就是为什么我们不能有一个
infinite number of size classes
大小类别的无限数量的
I suppose you know that'd be an
我想你 知道会是一个
interesting strategy to to think about
要想想有趣的策略
so you can't have an infinite number of
所以你不能有无限多
size classes but you could create a new
大小类，但你可以创建一个新的
size class for every new size that you
大小类为每一个新的大小，你
get and that that might work but it just
得到和那可能只是工作，但它
depends on the the range of these size
取决于这些尺寸的范围内
classes and the frequency and one
类的频率和一个
problem you might have is that you you
你 可能有 问题 的是你，你
would get maybe if you only get it
会得到也许如果你只得到它
depends on the distribution of your
取决于分配你的
sizes that you get if you're getting an
你得到，如果你得到 一个 尺寸
equal number if your distribution of
同等数量的，如果你的分布
sizes is fairly uniform that would
尺寸是 相当 一致的那 会
probably work pretty well if you're
可能 工作得很好，如果你
getting if you have requests if if you
得到，如果你有要求，如果你
have a lot of requests for different
有很多不同的 要求
size classes you have a lot of sort of
大小级你有很多种类的
wasted free lists I think right so it's
浪费空闲 列表，我认为正确的所以它的
a good question it depends on it depends
一个很好的问题这取决于它依赖
on your workload and there and that is
您的工作负荷和那里，这是
for that and that is a really useful
为 ，这是一个非常有用的
strategy for so you if you have really
战略，所以你如果有真
popular size classes in your request
流行的尺寸班在您的要求
then you could just make you know
那么你可以只让你知道
special case special case free lists to
特殊情况下的特殊情况下，免费名单
handle those requests and then and then
处理这些请求，然后再
let the other free list sort of handle a
让对方自由列表排序手柄的
wider range and imagine if you had a
更广泛的想象，如果你有一个
free list where all the blocks were the
空闲列表，所有的块是在
same it could be a lot more efficient
同样也可能是很多更有效
right because you won't Nate you only
正确的，因为你不仅会 内特你
need like a bit vector 1 1 bit for each
需要像一个位向量1 1比特用于每个
potential block to tell you whether it's
潜在的块来告诉你 它 是否
allocated or free so it could be very
分配或免费的，所以它可能是很
efficient you wouldn't you wouldn't need
高效的你不会你就不需要
to walk any any lists or anything
走任何任何 列表或任何
that's a good question and that's the
这是一个很好的问题 ，这就是
kind of thing you'll be thinking about
那种你会想的事情
when you do your Mallik lab is one of
当你做你的Mallik实验室是 一个
the there's a huge design space
在有一个巨大的设计空间
implementing malloc function and we just
实现malloc函数，我们只是
we just explored a one tiny part of it
我们只是探讨它的一个小部分
just now
现在
so with this implicit list we're going
所以用这种隐含列表中，我们要去
to need both the size of the block and
需要块的大小和
then its allocation status whether it's
那么它的分配状态无论 是
allocated or free now we could do this
分配或免费，现在我们可以做到这一点
in two words right but that would be
在两个单词权利， 但 会
wasteful
浪费
so the standard trick is to take
所以标准的关键是要采取
advantage of the fact that blocks have
优势的 事实，有块
to be aligned okay so this is actually
对齐好了，所以这实际上是
it's kind of a pain in the neck to
这是一种痛苦的在脖子上
always have to align these blocks but we
总是要调整这些块，但我们
can take advantage of it in this case
可以利用它在这种情况下，
and the reason is that if a block is
其原因 是，如果一个块是
aligned to some say 8 by 8 or 16 byte
由8个或16个字节对齐，有的说8
boundary then the lower order bits are
边界则低阶位是
always going to be 0 so if it's aligned
总是为0， 所以如果它对齐
to an 8 byte boundary the low order
为8字节边界的低位
three the three low order bits will
三个 低位3位将
always be 0 right 8 is 1 0 0 0 16 1 with
始终为0右8是1 0 0 0 16 1与
4 zeros 24 1 1 0 0 0 right so there any
4个零24 1 1 0 0 0 右 所以有 任何
any 8 byte any 8 byte aligned block has
任何8字节 任何8字节对齐 块具有
to be size 8 and it has to start on
是大小为8，它必须开始
address that's a multiple of 8 all right
地址是8 没事 多
so those the size so always the size of
所以那些大小 所以 总是大小
that block will always have 0 2 3 3 or 4
该块将总是具有 0 2 3 3或 4
a low-order bits set to 0 so we can take
设置0的低位 ，所以我们可以采取
it we can take advantage of that and
它可以利用 这一 优势 ，
we'll just make we'll just have one eye
我们只是做我们只能 一只 眼睛
we'll just have one header word and
我们只是 有一个报头字和
we'll use the lower order bit to store
我们将使用低阶 位存储
the allocation status okay and we can do
分配状态很好，而且我们 可以做
that because we know it's always zero so
因为我们 知道 它总是 零，因此
when we so we use that low order bit to
当我们使我们使用低次位
store the allocation status and then the
存储分配情况，然后
remaining bits correspond to the size
剩余的位对应于所述大小
and then whenever we want to extract the
然后，每当我们要提取的
size we just mask out this allocation
大小我们只是掩盖了这种分配
status and always set it to zero because
状态，并始终将其设置为零，因为
we know that it's zero
我们知道，这是零
so let's look in detail what given this
所以让我们看看具体是什么给这个
given this form of implicit list how we
给出这种形式的隐性列表 我们如何
might set things up so in this case
也许在这种情况下，一些事情， 从而
we're going to assume for bite words
我们要承担咬词
okay in size words and we're going to
好大小 的单词和我们要
align on eight byte boundaries okay so
八个字节边界对齐好了，
remember the payload of our blocks
记得我们的块的有效载荷
always has to start on an eight eight
总是要开始的八八
byte boundary so the way we do that is
字节边界，所以我们做到这一点的方法是
we create this unused word at the
我们在创建这个未使用的字
beginning of the heap that's aligned on
开始是对排列堆
this eight byte boundary and then that
这一个八字节边界，然后说
the first block in the heap starts at an
在堆中的第一个块开始于一个
offset of four from that from the
从从四个偏移
beginning of the heap so we have the
开始堆的，所以我们有
header which is is not aligned and then
报头是不对准，然后
we have the payload which follows in
我们有以下的有效载荷
this case at the payload of one one word
这种情况下，在一个一个字的有效载荷
and that starts on this that begins on
而开始于这一点，开始上
this this a word boundary and then the
这本单词边界 ， 然后
next block and and here we're indicating
下一个块，在这里我们要说明
a free block consisting of eight bytes
空闲块包括八个字节
and then that's followed by an allocated
然后是，再接一个分配
block to the one here of sixteen bytes
阻止这里的 十六个字节的一个
or four forwards
或4名 前锋
and now the payload is only two words so
现在的有效载荷只有两个字如此
we have to pad right all of our blocks
我们要垫右侧 我们 所有 的块
because we're assuming that they're
因为我们假定他们是
lined on eight byte boundary all of our
内衬八个字节边界，我们所有的
blocks have to be a multiple of size
块必须是尺寸的倍数
multiple of eight okay so here's the
所以这里 8 还好的多是中
case of internal fragmentation where we
内部分裂的情况下，我们
have this extra this extra block in
有这样的额外这个额外的块
order to maintain the alignment
为了保持对准
requirement so that that ensures that
要求，使得确保了
the next block payload starts at a an 8
下一个块的有效载荷开始于一个8
byte align boundary and so on and so we
字节 对齐边界 等等 ，所以我们
can walk this heap by just following
可以只是简单地跟着走这堆
these headers masking out the allocation
这些头屏蔽掉分配
bits and then we have this special
位，然后我们有这个特殊的
episode a load
事件负载
it's an allocated block of size 0 and
它的大小 为0 的分配块
this is a this is a trick this is a
这是这是 一招 ，这 是一个
trick you should use too so this and
欺骗你应该 使用 过 所以这和
we'll see when we look at coalescing why
我们会看到，当我们 看看为什么合并
this is why this helps but this this
这就是为什么这会有所帮助，但这个本
allocated block at the very end
在最后分配的块
eliminates some sort of special cases
消除某种 特殊情况
when we when we start to coalesce free
当 我们当我们 开始合并免费
blocks and we'll talk about that in just
块，我们将 在刚刚 谈论
a just a moment but you can finish your
一只是 一瞬间，但你可以完成你的
exists this allocated block of size 0 is
存在此分配的大小0的块是
also helpful in terminating when you're
也有利于在当你终止
walking this list you can you can check
走在这条列表，你可以，你可以查
for a size allocated block of size 0 to
对于大小为 0 的大小分配块
terminate your search
终止搜索
okay so given this kind of structure
好了，所以给这种 结构
then how do we find a free block okay
那么我们如何找到一个空闲块好吗
there's a number of different ways the
有许多不同的方式
first the first way which is called
首先这就是所谓的第一种方式
first the first fit is to search the
首先 第一嵌入是搜索
free list from the beginning and just
从一开始，只是空闲列表
look for the first block we can find
寻找 我们 可以发现 第一块
that satisfies the request so we're
满足要求，所以我们是
allocating we're asking for a block of
分配，我们现在需要 的块
size 10 we start at the beginning of the
10号，我们在开始 的 开始
heap and we walked a list we walked the
堆和我们走，我们 走 了 一个列表
heap looking for a free block that's at
堆找一个空闲块那是在
least size 10 and it needs to be
至少大小为10，它需要
actually and it needs to be 10 plus the
实际上，它需要为10 加
size of our header 2 so once so that's a
我们的头2所以一旦所以这是一个的大小
simple idea now some people have
简单的想法 ， 现在有些人 有
proposed an alternative called next fit
提出所谓的下一个合适的替代
so the idea here is that instead of
所以这里的想法是 ，与其
starting over each time from the
开始从每个时间超
beginning of the heap to find a block
堆开始找块
that sits we just pick up where we left
它位于 我们只是拿起 我们离开
off the last time okay so we look we
最后一 关 时间 好了， 我们来看看我们
scan the heap we find a block that's big
扫描堆，我们发现一个块 的大
enough to satisfy the request and then
足以满足该请求，然后
we remember where that where we left off
我们记住的是我们离开的地方
and the next time the request comes in
并在下 一次请求到来
we pick up the search starting where we
我们拿起搜索开始，我们
left off now this seems like would be a
离开现在这好像是一个
good idea but but studies pyrrha chol
好主意，但但研究皮拉哲
studies that people have done has shown
人们所做的研究表明
that this actually results in worse
这实际上会导致更糟糕
fragmentation so you know you can you
碎片化，所以你知道你可以
can consider it but it generally it's
可以考虑它，但它通常是
generally probably not the best thing to
通常可能不是最好的东西
do now another alternative is to find
现在要做的另一种 选择是找到
that the block in the heat a free block
的是， 在热的自由块的块
in the heap that's the best fit so look
在这最适合这么看堆
at in general look at all the blocks in
在 在所有块 一般 看
the heap and find the block that fits
堆和找到 适合 的块
the best okay so if we ask for 10 bytes
最好的好了，所以，如果 我们问了 10个字节
try to scan the heat for the block that
尝试扫描热量为块
has the closest to 10 bytes in it okay
有最接近它的10个字节 好吗
so that's called best fit and that's
所以这就是所谓的最适合的，这就是
that you can see it might be more it's
你可以看到它可能是更多的 是
sounds like it would be a lot more
听起来这将 是一个很多
expensive right because you'd have to
昂贵 正确的 ，因为你必须
look instead of just looking until you
看的 只是 寻找，直到你 ，而不是
find a fit you'd have to scan all the
找到 一个适合 你必须扫描所有的
free blocks and then pick the best one
空闲块，然后挑选出 最好 的 一个
okay but it has a nice property that it
不错，但它有一个很好的 特性， 它
improves memory utilization okay so if
提高内存的利用率好了，所以如果
this isn't this is a classic example the
这不，这是一个典型的 例子中
space time trade-off so it's slower but
时空权衡所以它的速度较慢，但
it improves improves our use of the
它改善提高了我们的使用
efficiency of the way we use memory
我们使用内存的方式效率
and there's a now we mentioned we
并有一个我们提到我们
mentioned an alternative way to organize
提到的一种替代的方式来组织
the free list using multiple free lists
使用 多个空闲列表 空闲列表
for different size classes now going
针对不同规模类 现在去
back to that example again if we had an
回到这个例子再次，如果我们有一个
infinite number of size classes one for
大小类别之一 的无限数量的
each size that would implement best fit
每个将实现最合适的尺寸
with a constant time search we don't
以恒定的时间搜索 ，我们不
know exactly which free list to get the
确切地知道哪些空闲列表以获得
block from the problem of course is how
从课程的问题 块 是如何
much memory such a organization would
多少内存这样的组织将
use but the interesting thing about
使用，但对有趣的事情
using multiple free lists is that the
使用 多个自由列表是，
more the more of these free lists you
以上的这些自由列表的越多，你
have the closer you get to a true best
有你越接近一个真正的最好的
fit
适合
okay so you can approach best fit and
好了，你可以接近最佳配合和
then at some point you begin to get
那么在某些时候你开始得到
diminishing returns so so that's another
收益递减 ，从而使这是另一个
sort of design decision is how many of
这类设计决策是多少
these multiple free lists do you need
这些多空闲列表你需要
and what sort of what what should be the
和什么样的应该是什么什么
size range is associated with them
尺寸范围是与它们 相关联
okay now the question now once we found
现在没事了，现在的问题，一旦我们发现
a block so the application has made a
所以应用一个块 作出了
call to malloc the malloc package is
调用的malloc malloc的包
looked in the free list that somehow
看着空闲列表，不知怎的
using some some policy it's identified a
使用一些相关政策它确定了
block that in which the requested blah a
阻止在其中所请求的 一个嗒嗒
free block in which the requested block
在其中所请求的块的空闲块
will fit okay so now what does it do it
将适合好吗所以现在这是什么 做
has to the malloc package has to
具有malloc的封装具有至
allocate it has to sort of take that
分配它具有某种采取
that so there's a question how does it
这所以有一个 问题是怎么做的
it could allocate the whole block and
它可以分配的整个块
return that back to the programmer or it
返回回程序员 或者
could it could choose to split out a
可能它可以选择打出一个
portion just only the portion of block
部分仅仅只有块的所述部分
that's needed and then create a smaller
多数民众赞成需要，然后创建一个较小
free block okay so for example if if we
空闲块好了，例如 ，如果，如果我们
if our if our application is has
如果我们的，如果我们的应用程序已经
requested a block of size 4 or I'm sorry
要求大小为4的块或对不起
it if the malloc package is determined
它如果malloc的包中检测
that that it in order to satisfy the
即，它在为了满足
application request it needs a block of
应用请求它需要的块
size 4 okay including the header then it
大小为4 行包括然后头部它
would look and it would try to find a
看起来，它会尝试寻找
free block of at least size forward so
至少大小的空闲块，从而向前
let's say it chooses this block for some
比方说，它选择这个块 的一些
reason maybe because it was a next fit
原因可能是因为它是下一个合适
picked up here so this free block is
拿起这里，所以这个可用块
actually six contains six words so the
其实 6包含 六个字所以
allocator has to decide whether just to
分配器必须决定是否只是为了
keep this block of size six and just
保持规模的此块六只
return that back to the to the
返回回至
application or whether to split that
应用程序或是否分割该
block into two blocks into an allocated
块分割成两个块成 分配
block of size four which it then returns
大小的块中 的四个它然后返回
to the application followed by a free
到应用程序， 然后免费
block of size two
尺寸的两个块
okay now another question is how to free
现在没事了另一个 问题是如何释放
a block so the application is requested
所以被请求应用程序的块
the allocate is called free and it's
该分配被称为免费的，它是
asked the allocator to free up a
问分配器，以腾出
particular block so this is pretty
特别块，所以这是很
simple so if we want to free up this
简单，所以如果我们要 腾出这
block you just clear the allocated flag
禁止您刚刚清除 分配标志
so if we want to free up the block we
所以，如果我们要 腾出 块我们
just created you just clear you just set
刚创建你只是 你只是设定 明确
the allocated bit to zero and you're
被分配位到零 ，你
done it's really simple but the problem
做它真的很简单 ，但问题
now is this this creates external
现在这个这就造成 外部
fragmentation so if now if if we just
碎片化，所以如果现在如果，如果我们 只是
free that block of size for what used to
空间大小的该块什么用
be a block of size six now consists of
是尺寸的块6现在由
two contiguous smaller blocks one of
两个连续的较小的块 中的 一个
size 4 and one of size 2 and so now if
大小为4和 现在如果 尺寸 2 的一个 等
that's followed by a request for five
即，再接一个五年的请求
blocks now we're stuck right so this but
块现在我们的权利，就是为了让这一点，但
we've got plenty of memory and it's even
我们有足够的内存，它甚至
worse in this case that memory is all
在这种情况下，更糟糕的是内存是所有
contiguous just because but just because
连续的，只是因为只是 因为
we just oh we just cleared the free
我们只是哦，我们 只是清除了 免费
block we didn't we didn't really notice
块中，我们没有，我们没有 真正注意到
that it was contiguous and so we ended
这是连续的，所以我们结束
up it was a situation where we have
起来，这是一个情况下，我们 有
these two continuous free blocks
这两个连续的自由块
so this this suggests that when we do
所以这这表明 ，当我们做
when we free up blocks that we somehow
当我们腾出块，我们不知何故
need to coalesce any neighboring blocks
需要合并任何相邻块
to keep blocks as big as possible right
保持块尽可能大的权利
so we cannot one of the invariance of
所以我们不能 的不变性之一
any decent allocator is that they're
任何像样的分配是，他们
never there never contiguous free blocks
从未从未有连续的空闲块
like this it's always a free block
这样它总是一个空闲块
followed by an allocated block okay so
其次 是 分配的块 好了，
the idea is that if we free a particular
这个想法是 ，如果我们 释放一个特定的
so here we have this allocated block and
所以在这里我们有这个分配的块和
if we free that block and we somehow
如果我们释放该块， 我们不知何故
have to check and see if there's any
要检查 ，看看 是否有任何
adjacent free blocks either following
相邻的空闲块以下任一
either neck either next in memory or
任一颈部或者在存储器或下
previous in memory and if there are we
以前在内存中，如果有我们
need to as part of the freeing process
需要的释放过程的一部分作为
we need to coalesce those two blocks
我们需要合并这两个区块
into a into a larger block the largest
成到一个更大的块最大
possible block possible now it's pretty
可能块可能现在这是很
easy if we're if we're asked to free
容易 ，如果我们如果我们要求免费
this block this green block it's pretty
此块这个绿色块 这是很
easy to check that the next block
易检查 下一个块
because you just we have the size we
因为你，我们有我们的大小
have this header so we know that the
包括这个头 ，所以我们知道，
next block starts at an offset of four
下一个块开始于 四个 偏移
so we just we just we just check we know
所以我们只是我们只是我们 只是检查 ，我们知道
and we know that the header for that
而我们知道，头部为
block is at an offset of four so we just
块是在四个偏移，所以我们只是
checked the allocated status of that
检查中所分配的状态
next block using the using the size
使用使用 尺寸下一个块
using the size field in our header but
使用我们的头规模场，但
what about the previous block what about
关于前一个块什么什么
this block how do we check that
这块我们怎么检查
well given given all that we talked
以及给定的给所有我们谈
about now the only thing the only way we
对，现在 我们 唯一的 必由之路
could do it would be to start at the
能做到这将 是在开始
beginning of the heap and now walk the
堆的开始，现在走
free list until we get to this current
免费列表，直到我们得到这个电流
block remembering the previous block so
阻止想起了以前的块 ，
each time we each time we traverse we
每次我们每次我们遍历 我们 的时间
remember the previous block okay so that
记得以前块好让
but that would be very inefficient right
但是这将是非常低效的权利
that would be that what that would make
那 会是什么 ，这将使
free linear in the size of the heat
在热的尺寸自由线性
because we'd have to in order to check
因为我们不得不以 检查
the previous block we'd have to walk
前面的块中，我们不得不走
starting
开始
very beginning and walked the entire
最开始， 走到整个
heap so the solution for that is was
堆所以该解决方案是WAS
proposed by a famous computer scientist
提出了一个著名的计算机 科学家
Don Knuth in 1973 and it's very clever
多恩·克努斯于1973年 ，它是非常聪明
it very simple like all really good
它很简单像所有真正的好
ideas it seems obvious that when you see
想法似乎很明显 ，当你看到
it but it turns out to be very clever
它，但它原来 是很聪明
and a very very useful technique and the
和一个非常非常有用的技术和
idea is just to replicate for each block
想法只是复制每个块
replicate the header block at the end of
复制头块在所述端部
the block ok so each block now contains
块确定，所以每 块现在包含
a header and a footer identical header
页眉和页脚相同报头
and footer and then this creates sort of
和页脚，然后这 将创建排序
an implicit backwards backwards link
隐式向后 倒退 链接
that we can use so now given given some
我们可以使用 所以现在给定的给予一定的
block that we want to given some block
我们要给予一定的块地
that we want to free we know that the
我们要释放我们知道，
the size of that block will just be one
该块的大小也只是 一个
one-word previous and memory so so we
一个字的前面 和记忆等等，所以我们
can just and its always a fixed fixed
正好可以 和 它始终有固定的固定
offset of one word so given you know
一个字的偏移，从而给你知道
given a pointer to the header of this
给定的一个指针的这个头
block we can look one word back to see
块，我们可以看一个背单词， 看
the size and the allocated allocation
大小和分配的分配
status of the previous block ok so we
先前块的状态确定，所以我们
added so that allows us to do that in
加入这样可以让我们做 ，在
constant time and so this footer is
常量时间，所以这 是页脚
sometimes called the boundary tag and
有时被称为 边界和标签
Knuth called it a boundary tag but we'll
克努特 称这是边界的标签，但我们会
just and or we can call it a footer to
公正， 或者我们可以称之为一个页脚
be sort of parallel with with the notion
可以用概念形式的平行
of a header but the key thing is that
头的， 但 关键的是，
it's just identical has the identical
它只是 相同的具有相同
size and allocation status
大小和分配状态
okay now so given yes question so the
还好现在这么给出肯定的问题，所以
question is if we want to have a
问题是，如果我们希望 有一个
boundary tag when we allocate a block do
当我们分配一块做边界标签
we need to set aside space for it and
我们需要预留 空间，并
answers yes most of the time I'll show
回答是 大部分的 时间 我会告诉
you one
你一个
I'll show you one optimization in a bit
我会告诉你在一个位一个优化
okay so given given this idea of a over
好了，所以给定给这个想法 的 上
the boundary tag and and and given that
边界标签，并和并考虑到
we have some allocated block that we
我们有一些分配的块，我们
want to free this yellow block yes
要释放此黄色块有
question
题
yeah we sorta quit yeah so just to
是的，我们八九不离十退出 呀所以才来
summarize the question you need to when
总之，你需要的时候的问题
you allocate when you're looking for
当您正在寻找分配
blocks that fit you have to include the
适合你的块必须包括
size of the header and the boundary tag
报头的大小和边界标记
it would you then you'd have and then
它会你，那么你就必须再
you'd have to insert padding to get a
你必须插入填充以获得
size a total block size that's a
大小共块大小，这是一个
multiple of that set of multiple that
这组 多的多的是
satisfies your alignment requirement
满足您的对齐要求
sorry yeah I mean it can yeah if you
对不起啊，我的意思是它可以是的，如果你
have it the question is wouldn't I use a
有它 的问题 是 我 岂不 使用
lot of memory and it can if again it
大量的内存，它可以如果再就
depends on the request the request
依赖于请求的请求
pattern is if the application is
图案是如果应用程序是
requesting lots of small payloads then
请求许多小的净荷然后
it's going to it's going to waste a lot
它会它会浪费很多
of memory if it's requesting big
内存如果它要求大
payloads not so bad
有效载荷没有那么糟糕
okay so given that we have some block
所以给出没关系，我们有一些块
that we want to free there's four cases
我们希望 释放有 4案件
that we need to consider when when
我们需要考虑的时候，当
coalescing the case where that the next
合并的情况下，未来
block is allocated and the previous
块分配和前
block is free is allocated a case where
块是免费被分配的情况下
the next block is free and the previous
下一个块是免费的，以前的
block is allocated case where the the
块被分配的情况下，其中 所述
previous block is free and the next
前一块是免费的，下一
block is allocated in the case where
块 的情况下 分配的
both the previous and next block are
前一个 和下一个 块是
free okay so in case one where we have
自由好了，万一有，我们有
our allocated block that we want to free
我们希望使我们的分配块
surrounded by two allocated blocks we
由两个分配块包围我们
don't do anything right because the only
不要做任何正确的，因为只有
call us free memory so so in this case
我们自由存储器中，以便所以在这种情况下，
we just set keep the size of the header
我们刚刚设置保持头的大小
and footer stays the same and we just
和页脚保持不变，我们只是
set the allocation status to shift free
设置分配状态转向免费
now if the if the next block is is free
现在如果要是下一块是免费的
and the previous block is allocated what
和先前块被分配什么
we do is we we check the boundary tag of
我们做的是我们，我们检查的边界标签
the the previous block and we see that
在前面的块，我们看到，
it's allocated so there's nothing to do
它的分配所以没有什么做
there we use the size to check the
还有我们使用尺寸 检查
allocation status of the next block we
下一个块，我们的分配状态
use n to jump to the header of the next
使用n 跳转到 下一个 的头
block we see that it's allocations
块中，我们看到它的分配
status is free so these two blocks need
状态是免费的，所以这两个块 需要
to be coalesced so we do that by just
以被合并，所以我们做 的只是
adding adding the two sizes together to
添加添加两种尺寸一起
create this larger coalesce block and
创建这个更大的聚结块和
setting its allocation status to zero
设置它的分配状态到零
now in the case where the previous block
在现在的情况下一个块
is is free again we we check the
是免费的，我们再次我们检查
boundary tech footer when we see that
边界高科技页脚当我们看到
it's we see it it's free so in this case
这是我们看到它是免费的，所以在这种情况下，
we create we have to update the size of
我们创建了必须更新的 大小
the the old the header of the old
在旧旧的头
previous block to create this now new
先前块创建这个新的现在
larger coalesce block and we and we
较大的聚结块，我们和我们
update the header and the boundary check
更新 标题和边界检查
footer accordingly
因此页脚
and then in the case where where both
然后在情况下其中两个
the previous and the next blocker are
前一个和下一个拦截器是
free we create a single block a single
免费，我们创建一个单一的块单
block that's the sum of all three of
块这三者的总和
those sizes
这些大小
okay so is that is that clear to
好了， 是该 清楚
everybody now if you point it out
大家现在如果你 指出来
correctly pointed out that boundary tags
正确地指出，边界标签
can create additional internal
可以创建 额外的内部
fragmentation because they're they're
碎片化，因为他们是他们
not part of payload so by definition
不有效载荷的一部分，以便通过 定义
they're if they're overhead and so you
他们，如果 他们的开销，所以你
might you might ask yourself are there
也许你会问自己 有没有
any cases where you don't need a
在这里你不需要任何情况下，
boundary tag
边界标签
so which which blocks need which blocks
所以这其中块需要哪些块
need a boundary tag
需要一个边界标签
you
您
could you get away with as an allocated
你可以逃脱作为一个分配
block need one
块 需要一个
yeah your if you're not going to if
是的你，如果你不 打算如果
you're not if you don't need to coalesce
你不是，如果你 不需要合并
and you don't need to that footer and
你不需要到页脚和
what kind of blocks don't you coalesce
你不凝聚什么样块
allocated blog
分配博客
so what so maybe we can maybe maybe we
所以什么，所以我们也许可以，也许，也许我们
don't need those at those boundary tech
不需要那些那些边界 高科技
footers on allocated blocks right just
在分配的块页脚权只是
on free blocks but then how are we going
在空闲块，但后来我们如何去
to determine that the previous block is
以确定前一个块是
allocated or free if an allocated block
分配或免费如果所分配的块
doesn't have a boundary tag footer yes
没有边界的标签页脚是
sorry well yeah you would give it one
对不起，好耶，你想给它一个
when you free it but somehow when we're
当你释放它，但不知何故，当我们
doing coalescing we need to check
做凝聚我们需要检查
somehow that that previous block whether
在某种程度上说，以前的块是否
it's allocated or free okay but how does
它的分配或自由 不错，但怎么做
it know it's whether it's a boundary tag
它知道 它是否 是一个边界标签
or not not sure no that's okay that's it
或者没有不知道没有那也没关系，就是这样
okay yep bingo you got it so remember
还好是的宾果你知道了，那么记住
this number remember because of our
这个数字还记得，因为 我们
alignment we've got we've got multiple
对准我们已经有了我们已经 得到了多个
at least three bits these three or four
至少三个比特这三个或四个
bits that are always zero we're only
位始终为零 ，我们只是
using one of them so why not use another
使用其中的一个，为什么不使用其他
one to contain the allocation status of
一个包含的分配状态
the previous block okay so very good
先前块好了，所以 非常 好
that was
这是
and so the idea so here's the block that
而这样的想法所以这里的块
we want to free and here's its header
我们要自由，这里是它的头
and we pass the P to it and we want to
我们 通过 在P它和我们想
we want to free it and we've got we've
我们要释放它 ，我们已经有了我们已经
got one bit we know that if we have a 8
得到了一个位，我们知道，如果我们有一个8
byte alignment we know that these are
字节对齐，我们知道这些都是
all implicitly 0 so we're using this is
所有隐含0，所以我们使用这
a allocated block that we want to free
我们希望释放一个分配的块
so it has an allocation status of 1 and
所以它具有1的分配状态和
let's use this let's use one of these
让我们用这个让我们用其中的一个
spare bits to indicate the allocation
空闲比特来表示分配
status of the previous block ok so far
先前块的状态OK 至今
if the previous block is is allocated
如果前面的块分配
then this would be a 1 and when we're
那么这将是一个1，当我们
checking to see whether we need to
检查， 看看我们是否需要
coalesce we just check that we just
凝聚我们只是检查，我们只是
check that that that second allocated
所检查的是第二所分配
bit the allocated bit of the previous
位以前的分配位
block and if it's 1 we don't need to
块，如果是1，我们并不 需要
know what its sizes ok we don't need to
知道它的大小 确定，我们并不 需要
know where that block is because we're
知道该 块是因为我们
not going to coalesce it okay so in that
不会在 这样 行不行合并会这样
we don't need so here we don't need a
我们不需要所以在这里我们并不需要一个
boundary tag for an allocated block but
所分配的块边界标签，但
now if that if that block is free it'll
现在如果，如果该块是免费的，它会
have a boundary tag so we'll check if
有边界的标签，所以我们去检查一下
that block is free then the
该块是免费，则
the allocation status will be will
分配情况是什么样子
indicate free and then we know we need
表明自由，那么我们就知道我们需要
to we need to coalesce and we're going
到我们需要 凝聚 ，我们要
to need we're going to need a boundary
需要我们将需要一个边界
tag because we need to know where that
标签，因为我们需要知道的是
block starts we need to know its size so
块开始，我们需要 知道它的大小，以便
that we can go back and and update this
我们可以回去 和更新本
size to include the you know the total
大小包括你知道总
coal left size and so that's two blocks
煤了尺寸等这两个区块
so that's that clear yep
所以这是说清楚是的
oh I just it's just the allocated bit so
哦，我只是把它仅仅是分配位 ，所以
zero means not allocated one means
零表示不分配一个手段
allocated
分配
oh why are those bits that are why are
哦，为什么 是那些为什么位
the bits always zero why
总是位0 为什么
okay so blocks have to be aligned to
好了，所以块必须对齐 ，以
eight byte boundaries
一个 八个 字节边界
okay oral payloads have to be aligned to
还好口服有效载荷必须对齐，以
eight byte boundaries okay that means
一个八个字节边界 还好这意味着
that that blocks have to be the size of
该块已经是大小
blocks has to be a multiple of eight
块必须是8的倍数
because it's the same thing it's when we
因为它是同样的 事情 是，当我们
were doing padding alignment instructs
在做填充对准指示
the next each block has to be a size has
下一每个块必须是一个具有大小
to be a multiple of eight so that the
是 八的倍数， 这样 的
the block that follows that in memory is
随后，在存储器是块
aligned properly okay
排列正确好吗
so you're guaranteed because of the
所以你保证， 因为
alignment requirement you're guaranteed
对齐要求你保证
that of eight or sixteen you're
这八个或十六 你
guarantee that the size of the blocks
保证块的大小
are always multiples of either 8 or 16
总是的8 或16的倍数
okay and so that and that so that
可以的， 使和 使
because that size is always a multiple
因为大小始终是一个 多
of eight or sixteen you're guaranteed
八个或十六你 保证
that either three or four four bits are
该三个或 四个四位是
all zeros
全部为零
[Music]
[音乐]
any other questions
还有其他问题吗
okay let me summarize then some key
好吧，让我 再 总结 一些关键
policies when one implementing an
当 一个执行的政策
allocator and i mentioned that there's
分配器和我提到 有
the design spaces for these things it's
设计空间，这些东西是
really large and really interesting
真正的大和 非常有趣
there's a lot of things that you a lot
有很多的事情，你有很多
of decisions that you have to make about
那你 必须做出 决定 有关
various policies so the first is the
各种政策，首先是
placement policy where when we when
放置策略，即当我们的时候
we're trying to find when we're trying
我们正在努力 ，当我们试图找到
to place a free block I mean and out
放置一个空闲块 我的意思是进出
when we're trying to place an allocated
当我们试图将分配的
block somewhere in a free block
阻挡在空闲块的地方
somewhere in the list
某处名单
what what what policy do we use first
什么什么我们用什么政策第一
fit next fit or best fit and generally
适合未来适合或最适合一般
these things a trade-off throughput for
这些东西权衡吞吐量
fragmentation all right so the the
碎片没事这样的
faster faster versions like
快了快了类似的版本
if you're willing to if you're willing
如果你愿意，如果你愿意
to deal with with lower throughput like
处理与类似的低级吞吐量
in the case of best fit and you can get
在最适合的情况下，你可以得到
better memory utilization now there are
更好的内存利用率现在有
interesting there are interesting ways
有趣的还有 有趣的方式
to improve the performance of best fit
改善最合适的性能
you might you might consider something
你可能你可能会考虑 什么
like good fit which is sort of a mix of
像般配是那种混合的
first fit and best fit so maybe maybe
首先适合和最适合的，所以也许也许
you only search the first you know a
你只能搜索你第一次知道
portion of the heap and then identify
堆的部分，然后确定
the best fit you know maybe instead of
你知道 的 ，也许不是 最合适
searching the entire heap you just
搜索 你 整个堆 刚
search some some portion of the heap and
查询的堆的一些一些部分和
then cut off the search and then within
再切断搜索，然后内
that region that you searched you pick
你搜索你选择的区域
the best block so that's something that
所以，最好的块的东西，
called good fit so that's that kind of
所谓良好的配合 ，这样的那种
approximates best fit or you can use
接近最适合， 也可以使用
these multiple free lists to approximate
这些多空闲列表近似
best fit and that's and then and there
最适合的，这就是再有
you the real advantage of using multiple
您 使用多个 真正的优势
free lists is that it not only improves
免费 列出的是， 它不仅 提高了
memory utilization but it improves
内存利用率，但它提高
performance too because the individual
性能也因为个人
list that you're looking for you know
你正在找你知道 名单
that they contain blocks that are close
它们含有接近块
to what you're asking for and since
你要问什么 ，自
you're dividing all the free blocks up
你将所有的空闲块了
among amongst multiple amongst multiple
其中在多个在多个
free lists those free lists will be
免费列出那些空闲列表会
shorter okay so your searches will take
短好了，你的搜索将采取
less time and your your probability of
更少的时间和你对你 的 概率
finding a block that fits goes up
找到适合的块上升
because you're segregating these
因为你这些分离
different size classes
不同大小班
now there's a good we also have to
现在有一个很好的，我们也有
decide on some splitting policy so when
决定一些分裂的政策，所以当
we find we find a free block that's big
我们发现，我们找到一个免费的块的 大
enough what do we do with the leftover
足够我们做什么用剩的
the leftover part of that block you know
你知道该块的剩余部分
once we placed our allocated block into
一旦我们把我们分配到块
that into that free block what do we do
那成空闲块 我们做什么
with the leftovers do we just leave the
与剩菜我们刚刚离开
leftover part in the block itself and
在块本身剩余部分和
return that back to the application
返回给应用程序
you know avoiding so that sort of
你知道这样避免诸如此类的
keeping keeping larger blocks or do we
保持保持较大的块还是我们的
go ahead and split it like like I showed
继续前进，就像我一样拆显示它
before and splitting we go ahead and
之前 和分裂我们继续 前进 ，
splitting that block and creating that
分裂阻断和创建
creating the original free block
创建原始空闲块
allocating a portion of it and then
分配它的一部分， 然后
creating a smaller free block so that's
创建一个较小的空闲块，这样的
you know that's a policy we may you may
你知道这是一个政策 ，我们可能会你可能
want to you may want to for small
想你可能要为小
requests for small payloads you may up
对于小型有效载荷要求您最多可以
to a certain size you may not want to
到一定的规模，你可能不希望
split so you may not you may decide not
拆分所以你可能不是你 可以决定不
to split blocks smaller you may not you
分裂块较小的你可能不是你
may decide not to create free blocks
可能决定不创建空闲块
that are smaller than some threshold and
小于某些阈值和
only splitting for four requests for
仅针对 四项要求分割
larger blocks and then there's there's a
较大的块，然后有有一个
coalescing policy now we've seen freeing
合并政策，现在我们已经看到了释放
is pretty quick now it's constant time
是相当快，现在它的恒定时间
because of the boundary tag footers but
因为边界标签 页脚 ， 但
you may you may want to you may want to
你可能你可能想你可能想
try to just speed that up even more by
尝试只是速度达到甚至 更多
by deferring the coalescing so you could
通过推迟凝聚，所以你可以
you can do coalescing it every time the
你能做到每次它凝聚
free is called like like we just looked
免费被称为像像我们刚刚看到
at or you could defer coalescing to some
在或者你可以推迟合并一些
later time you know maybe when you're
以后你也许知道，当你
scanning the free list when you're
扫描当你在空闲列表
scanning the free list looking set try
扫描空闲列表中寻找设定的尝试
trying to find trying to place an
试图找到努力的地方
allocated block in response to a malloc
响应分配块一个malloc
call maybe as you scan that free list
打电话也许你扫描自由列表
you could go ahead and do the coalescing
你可以继续 做的凝聚
at that time right so
在那个时候这样的权利
I'm not saying which one is better it's
我不是说哪一个更好它的
hard to it's really hard to argue for
很难这真的 很难说 了
the third coalescent getting the
第三成膜助剂 得到
constant time performance of a boundary
边界的固定时间性能
tag-based coalescing but it but it is an
基于标记的凝聚，但它，但它是一个
option okay so here's the summary then
选择 好了，所以这里的 总结，然后
of implicit lists this is the simplest
隐含的名单，这是最简单的
well it's a very simple kind of
那么 这是一个非常简单的 一种
allocator i it's it's the cost to
分配器我这是 它的成本
allocate is linear in the in the size of
分配是线性的中的大小
the heap a worst case that's the cost of
堆这是成本的 最坏情况
free is constant time even with
免费是恒定的时间甚至
coalescing memory usage will be will
合并的内存使用情况将是会
depend on that the placement policy
取决于放置策略
first fit next fit our best fit um
第一嵌入未来满足我们最合适的UM
it's not used in practice because of the
它不是， 因为 实践 中使用
linear time the linear time cost of
线性时间的线性时间成本
allocation okay but it it can be used in
配置不错，但它也可以用在
sort of special-purpose allocators where
某种特殊用途的分配器，其中
you have a small number of size classes
你有一个小的数目 大小班
maybe or you ever very you know that you
也许，或者你永远挺你知道你
have a very small or fairly small free
有一个非常小的或非常小的自由
list but the ideas of splitting and
名单，但分裂的思想和
coalescing that we looked at are general
凝聚我们看着是一般
to all allocators okay so the idea of a
所有分配器好了，所以 的想法
boundary tag called boundary tag based
边界标签叫做边界基于标签
coalescing is use used regardless of the
聚结是不管使用 的 使用
structure of your free list so implicit
您免费列表，从而隐含的结构
lists are useful to study because they
列表是学习，是因为他们有用
introduce some important concepts but
介绍一些重要的概念，但
generally they're not they're not
通常他们不是他们不
they're not that useful
他们没有多大用处
so next next class we'll look at some
所以接下来的下一节课，我们看一些
more sophisticated organizations of free
自由更复杂的组织
lists the explicit lists and multiple
列出了明确的名单和多
free lists in particular all right so
特别是免费列出了所有的权利，使
we'll see you then good luck on your
我们会看到你那么好 运气在 你的
shell lab due tonight and we'll see you
贝因实验室今晚，我们将看到你
on Thursday
星期四